<?xml version="1.0"?>
<BioSampleSet>                                      <BioSample submission_date="2012-01-30T18:47:56.987" last_update="2014-03-29T08:42:40.910" publication_date="2012-11-01T17:31:05.890" access="public" id="779736" accession="SAMN00779736">     <Ids>       <Id db="BioSample">SAMN00779736</Id>       <Id db="SRA" is_primary="1">SRS290758</Id>       <Id db="Data2Bio, LLC" db_label="Sample name">KI-42 Sample</Id>     </Ids>     <Description>       <Title>KI-MsEM0042</Title>       <Organism taxonomy_id="29719" taxonomy_name="Mentha spicata"/>       <Comment>         <Paragraph>*** SUBMISSION RECORD WAS PREPARED BY DATA2BIO ON BEHALF OF JOHN GREAVES (JOHN.GREAVES@KEMIN.COM), KEMIN INDUSTRIES, INC. *** KI-MsEM0042 was selected as an individual plant from a segregating population of spearmint plants based on its very high level (&amp;amp;gt;9% on a dry matter basis) of rosmarinic acid. Publically available segregating seed was planted in the greenhouse and plants were grown to a point where leaf tissue could be harvested. Leaf tissue was ground and extracted using solvents and rosmarinic acid levels of each plant in the population were compared to a purchased standard using a validated HPLC method. Vegetative cuttings of each greenhouse-grown plant were planted in the field for verification. Of 35 individual high rosmarinic acid plants selected from the population of &amp;amp;gt;200 plants, KI-MsEM0042 showed excellent vigorous growth which makes it an agronomically feasible crop to grow. Rhizomes of KI-MsEM0042 were used to vegetatively propagate this plant into a unique clonal line. The KI-MsEM0042 clonal line was tested under field conditions which confirmed the agronomic feasibility of this unique clonal line to produce rosmarinic acid in its leaf tissue at sufficient quantities to allow for economic extraction. KI-MsEM0042 was fully sequenced at the DNA level. Fresh leaves were grounded to fine powder using liquid nitrogen. Total gDNA was isolated using Qiagen DNeasy plant mini kit (Qiagen Cat# 69104)</Paragraph>       </Comment>     </Description>     <Owner>       <Name abbreviation="">Data2Bio</Name>       <Contacts>         <Contact email="support@data2bio.com">           <Name>             <First>Data2Bio</First>             <Last>www.data2bio.com</Last>           </Name>         </Contact>       </Contacts>     </Owner>     <Models>       <Model>Generic</Model>     </Models>     <Package>Generic</Package>     <Attributes/>     <Status status="live" when="2014-03-29T07:30:15"/>   </BioSample>                                      </BioSampleSet>
